In other words...
It's possible for us to plug
that hole in Wall Maria now.
The Scout Regiment hurry their
preparations for retaking Wall Maria.
Hell yeah! We did it, Eren!
Eren?
Let's hurry... make
weapons, and get going...
...to Shiganshina.
Seems if I inject this...
I'll turn into a Titan.
There came another...
One more thing to shape
their fate had been found.
Sorry I'm late.
Well?
Have we discovered
what's in the container?
The thing is...
With our technology, I'm afraid
we can't dig much deeper.
Like we've heard from Eren and Historia,
it seems to originate from
some sort of human bodily fluid.
However, it vaporizes when exposed
to air, making analysis difficult.
Whoever made it must have had
technology far superior to ours.
If it was the Reiss family,
I can't imagine how...
Hmm...
In that case, instead
of tampering with it,
we should use it to achieve
our current objective.
But who do we entrust it to?
Erwin, to you?
No...
I'm no more than a wounded soldier.
This box belongs with one of our elite
soldiers who has the best odds of survival.
Levi, would you keep it?
If it's an order, just say so.
Why even ask the question?
We can't predict in what situation
we'll have to use this.
We'll be relying on you
to make a decision on the fly.
Judging when and who to use it on
will be for you to choose.
Can we leave that to you?
If this dream of yours comes true,
what will you do then?
I... don't know.
I won't until it happens.
I see... All right.
I'll do it.
By the way, I'd like to unveil
that work of mine soon.
Have you given it thought?
You still haven't given up on that?
If the public saw that
repulsive display,
trust in the military
would hit rock bottom.
You don't know art when you see it.
"Night of the Battle to Retake the Wall"
In other words, Eren's
father, Grisha Jaeger...
...is likely a human who came
from outside the walls.
Yes.
Just like Annie, Reiner, and Bertholdt,
he possessed the Power of the Titans.
But different from those three, he was
supportive of humanity within the walls.
If he was so interested to know
about the Scouts and such,
we could've used more
of that support of his.
I wonder...
From the moment he entered the walls,
he was searching for the royal
family all alone, I'm sure.
And that...
That's not something you do
without incredible resolve.
That same father wanted to show his
10-year-old son, eager to join the Scouts,
the basement of their house.
On death's door, he said the truth
of it all was... in the basement.
What in the world do you
think is down there?
Things which mustn't be said.
No...
Things Grisha Jaeger couldn't say,
even if he wanted to.
That which the First Reiss King
wiped from our memories...
...memories of our world...
...is what I hope, but...
Pondering about it here
won't accomplish much.
The preparations finished today.
The operation to retake
Wall Maria starts in two days.
Want to know what's in the basement?
Let's go see for ourselves.
Isn't that what Scouts do?
Let all your squads know.
Right. Keeping it secret of course, yeah?
On a day like this,
we deserve some meat, right?
Good idea. Gotta show those kids
us adults can be counted on.
What about Commander Sadies
keeping secrets from us?
Forget about him.
We don't have time to deal with it.
I'm shocked, Hange. You used to adore him!
Shut up!
What is it, Levi?
It's a bit hasty, but...
What will you do after
retaking Wall Maria?
I'd guess a defense plan
comes first, but...
After that?
Eliminating threats.
Outside the walls, there seems to be
someone hoping Titans will eat us all.
Of course, the answer to who
is in the basement, I imagine.
It's as I said earlier.
We'll plan that after the basement.
I'm asking this because you
might not live that long.
You can't exactly move like you used to.
Let Hange call the shots.
You'll just be dead weight.
Let the good news come to you.
We'll tell the others I
argued till you gave in.
No... That's actually what I intend.
Fine with that?
I'm not.
I'm fine being food. Use me as bait.
The chain of command still remains.
If I'm gone, then Hange.
If Hange's gone, the next.
It's true, this operation
will be dangerous, but...
...to humanity, it's more
important than anything else.
That's why I've gone to such lengths.
This is all my plan.
If I don't do it, the
success rate will plummet.
That's right. The operation
might fail, but...
If you bite the dust in
the process, we're doomed.
So just sit at your desk
and keep using your head.
That's the last thing
the Titans would want.
And for humanity,
it's the best thing going for us.
No, you're wrong.
Our best option is for
me to gamble it all...
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Hold up...
Keep using that bluff around me
and I'll break both of your damn legs.
I'll make it nice and easy
to attach them later.
But the operation to retake Wall Maria
will proceed with you weeping here.
It'll be a bitch to get
to the toilet though.
I'd like to avoid that.
What you're saying is right.
A wounded soldier should
stay off the battlefield.
However...
There will come a moment when
we learn the truth of our world...
...and I must be there for it.
Is it that important to you?
More than your legs?
Yes.
More than humanity's victory?
I see...
Erwin...
I'll trust your judgment.
This may be a special night, but...
let's not let the public find out!
Behave like soldiers
without causing a ruckus!
Eh? Meat?
What? Is this... meat?
Am I dreaming?
Tonight's the night before
we retake Wall Maria!
Cheers!
Huh?! Wait!
Calm down! We'll split it evenly!
Hey! That big piece counts as two!
Hell no!
But you suck with the spear!
You're useless, so gimme yours!
Say what?!
Don't you start pulling
that shit, potato girl!
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
Cut it out, Sasha!
I... I don't wanna have to kill you!
You can't eat the whole thing alone!
You're eating me! Eating me! Eating me!
Sasha! That meat is Jean!
Have you lost your mind?!
Do the Scouts never get fed any meat?
Pathetic...
Conny, would you knock Sasha out already?
I'm trying!
She should be unconscious,
but she's still moving!
Hey, I think we've got casualties.
Whose brilliant idea was it to serve meat?
Sorry. But now we know
blowing the food budget
for two months in one
night results in this.
That should do it.
She finally ran out of energy.
Can you believe this freak?
And to think she once offered
to share meat with everyone.
Huh? When?
Four months ago, when we were
servicing the cannons.
I brought some meat from
the officers' storehouse!
It'll be fine!
We can just raise more cattle and
sheep once we retake our land!
It's happening again!
The Titans are going to get in!
It disappeared!
I thought... I felt sorry for you.
Hey.
Only four months have
passed since back then?
Only four months.
But think, in just four months,
we're in Squad Levi.
We climbed the ranks in a flash.
It's 'cuz you're a genius.
Damn straight I am.
Let's eat before our food gets cold.
Don't you see?
You're the rear guard 'cuz
you've got no experience.
I understand that I may be weak, but...
Isn't the vanguard the best place
to learn how the enemy moves?
What's this? Trying to act all tough
talking about self-sacrifice?
But if we're all not of that mentality,
how will we be effective as a unit?
Listen here... Everyone
starts out as a recruit.
If we throw recruits
into battle like cannon
fodder, they'll all
be too dead to learn.
Which is why it's your job to
sit in the back and study,
so you can come home in one piece.
But the most useless of all is the suicidal
maniac who only knows how to charge in.
Right?
Jean... Who do you mean by that?
Who else but you?
You suicidal maniac.
Actually, I found something out recently.
I'm quite a normal person, you know?
So if you're saying that to me,
that just makes you a coward, Jean.
You're so full of yourself, you pig shit!
You trying to grow out the hair
on your mane, horse face?!
Hey, what the...?
Just don't hit the face.
You jerk!
You're ripping it, ass!
What the hell are they doing?
You bastard!
Show 'em what you've got!
He's losing ground!
Looks like something started.
And here I told 'em to behave...
But seriously...
Ah?
If you didn't have Titan powers,
you'd be dead ten times over.
And every time, Mikasa would
swoop in to save your ass.
If you insist on being suicidal...
...I'll just have to kill you!
That's something I'll
have to take to heart!
You should start showing
your mom some respect, Jean-boy!
Would you forget that?!
Blargh!
Shouldn't we stop them?
No...
I think it's fine.
Why isn't anybody stopping us?
How long will this go on for?
Shit... I think I'm gonna
barf up that meat.
Hey.
You're all too damn rowdy.
Go to sleep.
And clean that up.
Yes, sir!
Ouch...
It's weird when I say it, but...
Shouldn't you guys watch out for me more?
I knew if you got hurt it would
heal up quick, so I just watched.
That's so cruel.
You're the one who incited it.
But... at least you're spunky again.
I'm glad we met the commandant.
I... It doesn't...
Whether I'm spunky or not,
I'll do what I have to do.
But, yeah...
It's easier now.
Kept thinking about stuff I can't change.
And wondering why I can't be
strong like Mikasa and Levi...
I was jealous.
But even you and the captain...
alone, you can't do much.
Which is why we've all gotta
find the things we can do.
And by joining together,
that's what makes us powerful.
Every person is different.
And it's all for times like this.
Yeah...
I think you're right.
Once we retake Wall Maria...
...and defeat all the
enemies coming for us...
...will they come back?
Those days...
We'll bring it back.
But some things are forever changed.
We'll make them pay for that.
Yeah.
But there's more than that.
The sea...
A salt lake so big that merchants
could spend their whole lives
and still not get all the salt.
There's more than just
Titans outside the walls.
Fiery water, lands of
ice, sandy snowfields...
I joined the Scouts so
I could see all that.
Y-Yeah. You sure did.
Right?!
Let's start by seeing the sea!
You still doubt that it's real, Eren!
You'll see! It does exist!
All right then.
Guess we'll have to go see.
It's a promise, then!
You have to!
...Yet another conversation only you two
get... We can explore the outside world!
It's gotta be way bigger
than inside the walls!
Okay, I get it.
Just before sunset...
It's finally time.
Hey!
Hange!
Good luck!
Flegel?
Take back Wall Maria for us!
The future of humanity is in your hands!
Captain Levi!
Thank you for saving our city!
You all come back in
one piece, all right?!
But go and reclaim our territory!
Someone's got a big mouth.
Well, with the commotion we made,
of course they'd find out.
The thing is, all that meat we ordered
was from the Reeves Company.
Damn that Flegel.
...Yeah! You can count on us!
...You know we will!
How long's it been since the Scouts
got a send-off like this?
Who knows? I don't think we've ever...
As far as I'm aware, this is a first.
The final operation to
retake Wall Maria...
...will now commence!
Advance!
You guys...
Do you have the faintest damn clue...
...what you're doing?!